

## Skills

## Top 1% Contributor on Stack Overflow Exceptional Achievements in the **Programming Community**

JavaScript/TypeScript (> 9 years)

Web, Desktop, and Mobile Applications (React, Vue, Angular, Svelte)

**\* \* \* \* \*** 

C# Development (> 20 years)

Web, Desktop, Server, and Mobile **Applications** 

APIs (> 15 years)

GraphQL & REST APIs **\* \* \* \* \*** 

SQL Databases (> 9 years)

PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server,

MariaDB, MySQL, SQLite  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$ 

NoSQL Databases (> 15 years) MongoDB, Firebase, Redis

DevOps (> 9 years)

GitLab  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$ 

Serverless (> 9 years) AWS Lambda, Google Cloud Functions,

**Azure Functions** 

Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions,

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$ 

Edge Computing (> 1 year) Edge Functions & Edge Runtime

Spoken Languages

German

**English** 

## **Denis Knaack**

Software Development & Consulting

& +49 170 5867448 • @ denis@knaack.it • ♂ https://www.knaack.it

**Profiles** 

in /denisknaack

👔 /dknaack

/knaackee

Okt. 2003 – Jan. 2008

Jan. 2008 – Apr. 2011

Nov. 2012 - Feb. 2015

Steinberg am See, DE

2000 - 2003

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

Figma

NodeJS / Typescript

**Typescript** 

**React Native** 

NodeJS / Typescript

Regensburg, DE

Throughout my career, I have worked with various programming languages, tools, and services. My passion for technology motivated me to continually evolve. Customers appreciate my ability to integrate new technologies and provide solutions that often exceed their objectives. As the CTO and co-founder of a startup, I gained valuable insights into

business life. I use these experiences to advise teams and develop strategies that align with business goals. In this role, I was also involved in the creation and acquisition of a software patent.

Professional Experience GoNamic GmbH

Manager Software Development Regensburg, DE

SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG

SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG

Senior Manager Software Development

Manager Software Development Regensburg, DE Apr. 2011 - Nov. 2012

Omniga GmbH & Co. KG

Software Development Professional Regensburg, DE KNAACK.IT Feb. 2015 - heute

Software Development & Consulting (self employed)

Education

BSZ Matthäus Runtinger BSIII

Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung (IT Specialist in

Application Development)

and Microsoft SQL Database.

Projects (Excerpt) Fintech Startup

Distribution)

Development of backend solutions and APIs for a fintech startup, utilizing C#

Automated Email Dispatch (Implementation of Automated Invoice Email

Implementation of an automated system for emailing invoices, developed in

Visa Policy Update Implementation of new requirements for visa payment processing using C#.

Website Relaunch

Redevelopment and modernization of a website using C#. **Password Validation** 

Transition from plain text passwords to hashed and salted passwords,

implemented in C#. Mailgun Integration

Consulting GraphQL

GraphQL Backend

Plug-In System

Auto-Updater

TypeScript.

UI / UX

GraphQL Backend

developed in TypeScript.

COVID Scanner App

Implementation and documentation.

Advising a development team on GraphQL implementation and best practices.

Development of a sample implementation for a GraphQL backend using NodeJS and TypeScript.

**NNTP Client** 

Development of an NNTP client using C#.

Enhancement of a Windows client with a plug-in system, developed in C#.

Implementation of an automatic update system for a Windows application.

Creation of an app for scanning and displaying information from QR codes, developed with React Native.

**Marketing Website** React / Typescript

Al Chatbot React / Typescript

Development of a website for a mid-sized company, utilizing React and

Design and integration of an AI chatbot based on ChatGPT, implemented using React and TypeScript.

Creation and presentation of a user interface for a web application using Figma.

Automatic Update Feature for Electron App **NodeJS** Development of a self-updating mechanism tailored for an Electron

application, utilizing NodeJS.

Development of an API with integration to a PostgreSQL database, implemented using NodeJS and TypeScript.

**Chrome Extension** Development of a Chrome extension with ChatGPT integration, implemented in

TypeScript.

**Outlook Plugin** Typescript Creation of a plugin for easier management of filters and folders in Outlook,

NodeJS / Electron / Typescript **Desktop Client** 

Development of a cross-platform client for Windows, Mac, and Linux for processing and analyzing AAF files, using NodeJS, Electron, TypeScript, and C#.

CI / CD Github Actions

Delivery (CI/CD) process for a team with various projects, utilizing GitHub Actions. React / Typescript **Progressive Web App** 

Creation and implementation of a Continuous Integration and Continuous

Development of a Progressive Web App (installable, offline-ready) with

features including authentication, email sending, and more, built using React and TypeScript.